RG 004:162, Winchester Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Winchester Probate Court records
1838-1924
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Winchester District)
33.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1838-1924; Probate files, 1838-1912.
RG004_162
1931-004, 2011-090
Historical Note
Winchester, Litchfield County, Town named 1733, established in May 1771, City of Winsted incorporated January 1917
The Winchester Probate District was constituted May 31, 1838 from the Norfolk Probate District. It also included the municipality of Colebrook from May 31, 1838 to January 4, 2011. The Winchester Probate District merged with the New Hartford and Torrington Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Torrington Area Probate District which serves the municipalities of Barkhamsted, Colebrook, Goshen, Hartland, New Hartford, Torrington, and Winchester.
Town of Winchester (which includes the City of Winsted) Probate District chronology:
May 1733 - May 1769, Hartford District
May 1769 - May 1779, Simsbury District
May 1779 - May 30, 1838, Norfolk District
May 31, 1838 - January 4, 2011, Winchester District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Torrington Area District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, vol. 1-37, 1838-1924. Contact the probate court to access original record books after volume 37. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1838-1912. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1838-1912 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-090 are numbered from 1-37.
Probate files in accession 1931-004 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1934-001 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Colebrook; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Winchester
Places:
Colebrook (Conn.); Winchester (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-090, Record books, 1838-1924, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1946 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes A, 2-10, 12-14, 16, 19, 21, 23, 25, 27, 29, 31, 35, 1838-1918; probate files, 1838-1880; and inventory control book were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1931-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): October 13, 1931 (1838-1912).
The record books in accession 2011-090 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 3, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1838-1924; 19.5 cubic feet (37 volumes); 2011-090
  - Records, 1838-1844 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1843-1850 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1849-1857 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1858-1868 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1856-1859 (Volume 5)
  - Orders, 1856-1866 (Volume 6)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Orders, 1866-1874 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1868-1875 (Volume 8)
  - Orders, 1874-1880 (Volume 9)
    On spine: Records
  - Records, 1875-1879 (Volume 10)
  - Orders, 1880-1885 (Volume 11)
    On spine: "Records
  - Records, 1880-1883 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1883-1885 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1885-1889 (Volume 14)
  - Orders, 1885-1888 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1888-1890 (Volume 16)
  - Orders, 1888-1891 (Volume 17)
  - Bonds, 1888-1907 (Volume 18)
    On spine "Records"
  - Records, 1890-1893, 1895 (Volume 19)
  - Orders, 1892-1894 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1893-1895 (Volume 21)
  - Orders, 1894-1897 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1895-1897, 1906 (Volume 23)
  - Orders, 1897-1899 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1897-1899, 1903, 1906 (Volume 25)
  - Orders, 1899-1902 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1899-1904, 1906 (Volume 27)
  - Orders, 1902-1905 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1904-1907 (Volume 29)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders, 1905-1907 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1907-1913 (Volume 31)
  - Orders, 1907-1912 (Volume 32)
  - Bonds, 1907-1924 (Volume 33)
  - Orders, 1911-1914 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1912-1918 (Volume 35)
  - Orders, 1914-1917 (Volume 36)
  - Orders, 1917-1921 (Volume 37)
- Probate files, 1838-1912; 14.25 cubic feet; 1931-004
  - Abbott - Babock (Drawer 1)
  - Baglin - Barry (Drawer 2)
  - Bartholomew - Bennett (Drawer 3)
  - Bidwell - Bronson, F. (Drawer 4)
  - Bronson, G. - Burke (Drawer 5)
  - Burkett - Carpenter (Drawer 6)
  - Carr - Claflin (Drawer 7)
  - Clark - Coffee (Drawer 8)
  - Coleman - Cowles (Drawer 9)
  - Coy - Davis (Drawer 10)
  - Davison - Donohey (Drawer 11)
  - Donovan - Dyson (Drawer 12)
  - Eades - Fordyce (Drawer 13)
  - Fosket - Gilbert (Drawer 14)
  - Gillett - Gunther (Drawer 15)
  - Haley - Hazzard (Drawer 16)
  - Healey - Holabird (Drawer 17)
  - Holcomb - Hull (Drawer 18)
  - Hummiston - Hurlbut, R. (Drawer 19)
  - Hurlbut, S. - Jopp (Drawer 20)
  - Jordon - Lathrop (Drawer 21)
  - Lavin - MacAlpine (Drawer 22)
  - MacArthy - Mead (Drawer 23)
  - Medick - Munson (Drawer 24)
  - Murphy - O'Brien (Drawer 25)
  - O'Conner - Pease (Drawer 26)
  - Peck - Phelps, J. (Drawer 27)
  - Phelps, K. - Pond (Drawer 28)
  - Poole - Reutter (Drawer 29)
  - Reynolds - Rockwell, M. (Drawer 30)
  - Rockwell, N. - Rugg (Drawer 31)
  - Russell - Sawyer (Drawer 32)
  - Scanlon - Skinner J. (Drawer 33)
  - Skinner, K. - Smith, O. (Drawer 34)
  - Smith, P. - Starks (Drawer 35)
  - Stebbins - Sulz (Drawer 36)
  - Swan - Thebo (Drawer 37)
  - Thomas - Turton (Drawer 38)
  - Tuttle - Watson (Drawer 39)
  - Wattles - Whealon (Drawer 40)
  - Wheeler - Whittaker (Drawer 41)
  - Wickham - Woodford (Drawer 42)
  - Woodhead - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 43)
- Inventory Control Book, 1838-1912; T003073
  Index of the probate files in accession 1931-004
  Also known as the Godard Digest